<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><aiml version="1.0"><category><pattern>IS CEG OPEN * WEEKENDS</pattern><template>No, ceg is not open on weekends</template></category><category><pattern>DOES CEG PUBLISH ANY MAGAZINES</pattern><template>yes ceg publishes a magazine that illustrates the emerging technologies in digital world</template></category><category><pattern>* CEG * E BOOK</pattern><template>Yes ceg offers e-books on ebasta. it contains a lot of academic books.</template></category><category><pattern>CEG IS AN INITIATIVE BY</pattern><template>Meity</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT WAS THE NEED OF CEG</pattern><template>to make people aware about new technologies so that they can use in normal life.</template></category><category><pattern> * APPS * CEG *</pattern><template>Digilocker, eSushrut, eBasta, eHastakshar, eSampark are some examples</template></category><category><pattern>CAN COLLEGE STUDENTS VISIT CEG</pattern><template>YES!!</template></category><category><pattern>IS THERE ANY CHARGE TO VISIT CEG</pattern><template>NO</template></category><category><pattern>WHY SHOULD I VISIT CEG</pattern><template>to know more about government initiatives towards digital india</template></category><category><pattern>HOW CAN I CONTACT CEG</pattern><template>You can check out the website for e-governace and you can also follow ceg facebook page</template></category><category><pattern>* MORE INFORMATION ON CEG</pattern><template>refer the website for more details</template></category><category><pattern>* DIGILOCKER</pattern><template>an app that stores your most important informations securely such as aadhar, marksheet, driving license.</template></category><category><pattern> * CEG LOCATED</pattern><template>Centre for e-Governance (CeG) is located in the first floor of Electronics Niketan, 6 CGO Complex (near Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium), Lodhi Road, New Delhi.</template></category><category><pattern>WHERE IS CEG</pattern><template>Centre for e-Governance (CeG) is located in the first floor of Electronics Niketan, 6 CGO Complex (near Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium), Lodhi Road, New Delhi.</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT IS THE NEAREST METRO STATION TO CEG</pattern><template>Jawahar Lal Nehru Stadium</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT DOES CEG DO</pattern><template>The Centre has been envisaged as the platform for showcasing advancement in ICT domain especially in e-Governance by demonstrating applications from states, central line ministries, MeitY organizations and other implementing agencies.</template></category><category><pattern>WHO HAS ESTABLISHED CEG</pattern><template>Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) has established the `Centre for e-Governance’ (CeG)Centre for e-Governance</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT DOES CEG STAND FOR</pattern><template>Centre for e-Governance</template></category><category><pattern>FULL FORM OF CEG</pattern><template>Centre for e-Governance</template></category><category><pattern>TELL ME SOMETHING ABOUT CEG</pattern><template>The CeG showcases applications, demonstrations and presentations that reflect the progress achieved in the implementation and usage of e-Governance. It covers successful and high impact e-Gov applications and content based on improved citizen service delivery, innovativeness, cost effectiveness and overall impact in fulfilling developmental objectives of the government.</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT IS CEG</pattern><template>The Centre for e-Governance provides a unique platform for wider dissemination of awareness regarding successful e-Governance initiatives in the country as well as the roadmap for implementation of e-Governance. CeG would also undertake hosting of important Seminars/ Conferences and other similar awareness programs to reach out to the common man. The CeG is a part of the “Awareness and Communication” activity under National e-Governance Plan (NeGP)</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT ARE THE INITIATIVES OF CEG</pattern><template>Some of the initiatives which are being demonstrated are: Bharat Interface for money, Common Services Centre, Digilocker, eSushrut, eBasta, eHastakshar, eSampark, India.gov.in, Meghraj, Mkavach, PayGov</template></category><category><pattern>IS CEG OPEN FOR VISITS</pattern><template>Yes CeG is open for visits. The Centre is open for visit by common citizens, student community, strategists and experts in the field of governance and also to the policy-makers as well. Visitors to the Centre would have a first hand knowledge on various e-Governance initiatives in the country and hands-on experience on the web-enabled e-services being delivered in various parts of the country. The visitor is also given opportunity to experience different e-services as well as digitally record his / her impressions of the CeG.</template></category><category><pattern>HOW CAN ONE VISIT CEG</pattern><template>To facilitate the visit a Requisition Form for Application for the Visit as given below, required to be appropriately filled in and to be sent to the Centre for e-Governance through e-mail in advance.</template></category><category><pattern>DOES CEG OFFERS JOB OPPORTUNITIES</pattern><template>No ceg does not offer any job facilities but it does offer interships to college students.</template></category><category><pattern>WHAT IS THE NEED OF CEG</pattern><template>it is considered to be extremely important to reach out common people at large `(People are the Purpose)’ and disseminate information on the projects to assess impact of these projects on peoples’ daily life.</template></category><category><pattern>WHO IS THE HEAD OF CEG</pattern><template>Head of ceg is Dr. A.K.Garg Director (e-Governance, Innovation and IPR)</template></category><category><pattern>DOES CEG ORGANISE ANY WORKSHOP</pattern><that>WHAT DO YOU FEED YOUR *</that><template>The CeG showcases applications, demonstrations and presentations that reflect the progress achieved in the implementation and usage of e-Governance. It covers successful and high impact e-Gov applications and content based on improved citizen service delivery, innovativeness, cost effectiveness and overall impact in fulfilling developmental objectives of the government. Also displayed are various social sector initiatives relating to health and education.</template></category><category><pattern>HOW HAS CEG PAVED WAY FOR DIGITAL INDIA</pattern><template>It covers successful and high impact e-Gov applications and content based on improved citizen service delivery, innovativeness, cost effectiveness and overall impact in fulfilling developmental objectives of the government. Also displayed are various social sector initiatives relating to health and education.</template></category></aiml>